<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Department of Bad Ideas</title>
    <description>The Department of Bad Ideas is a podcast about policy, disconnected from reality.
In each episode, our guests tell us how they'd fix public policy problems in the most impractical, unpalatable and impossible ways.
Each episode of the Department of Bad Ideas consists of four rounds.
1. The first round is the “Impossible Implementation Unit”. Our guests have 5 minutes to pitch the solution to a policy problem they're given ahead of time. The problem could be anything from the ridiculous to the real: like preparing for an alien invasion, or solving a shortage of teachers in schools. Their solution has to be entirely impossible to implement, but so attractive that everyone would want to do it that way.
2. The second round is the “Unsaleable Policy Division”. Our guests are given another policy problem ahead of time, and they'll have another 5 minutes each to pitch their solution. This time the idea has to be brilliantly practical, but political kryptonite. It has to be so unpalatable that any senior official or minister would recoil in horror at the very idea of fixing that problem with that particular solution.
3. The third round is a chance to pitch the “The Big Idea”. Our guests get 5 minutes to pitch a totally original idea to solve any problem they like. It doesn't matter how ridiculous the problem is; they just have to pitch the biggest, boldest, best solution they have to fix it.
4. The final, bonus round is “In the Thick of It”. Instead of prepreared pitches to known problems, our guests will take part in an unscripted quick fire round. We’ll give our guests a series of policy problems, and they have to describe a solution to it on the fly for a minute.
Throughout the episode, points are awarded for originality, presentation, practicality and political attractiveness. In the final round, additional points are awarded for each second the guest speaks without repetition or hesitation.</description>
    <link>https://badideas.podcast.johnpe.art/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://badideas.podcast.johnpe.art/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:36:30 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:36:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>What’s all this about then?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’ve found your way to this blog post, you’ve stumbled upon a brand new podcast. It’s a podcast about public policy as game show, and it’s called the &lt;strong&gt;Department of Bad Ideas&lt;/strong&gt;. Welcome!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m the creator and soon-to-be host of this peculiar endeavour and I’m here to tell you a bit about what you can expect on this auditory rollercoaster into the world of public policy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;in-a-nutshell&quot;&gt;In a nutshell&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Department of Bad Ideas is a podcast about public policy, but disconnected from reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People working in public policy – like me and some of the guests you’ll hear from – usually have to solve complex problems within ever tighter constraints. This podcast is about exploring what happens when you take most of the constraints away and ask people to reach for the most outrageous ideas they can think of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In each episode, our guests will engage in a battle of policy ideation and wits. Their task is to come up with the best-worst ideas possible. They have to be impractical, unpalatable or entirely nonsensical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-to-expect&quot;&gt;What to expect&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each episode will consist of four rounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In each of the first two rounds, guests are given a policy problem ahead of time that they will be asked to solve. The problem could be anything from the ridiculous to the real: like preparing for an alien invasion, or solving a shortage of teachers in schools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forewarned with both problems, they will have five minutes in each round to pitch their solution. In round one, our guests will pitch the most impractical but most politically attractive idea they can think of to solve the problem. In the second round, they have to do the opposite: find a brilliantly practical idea that will crash and burn when it reaches the Red Box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the third round, our guests will pitch their Big Idea. They’ll get to suggest the biggest, boldest and best solution they can think of to any problem they want to try to fix. The problem can be totally real or totally ridiculous, but the solution must be brilliant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final round will be different: instead of preprepared pitches, guests will have to think on their feet. They’ll be given more policy problems to solve — but this time they’ll do it on the fly. Just to make things more difficult, they’ll have to do it without hesitation or repetition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In each round, points are awarded for originality, presentation, practicality and political attractiveness; and for the final round they get an extra point for every second they speak without repetition or hesitation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of each round, I’ll award points for originality, presentation, practicality and political attractiveness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we’re all done, I total up the points. Points mean absolutely nothing, but our guests can at least gloat at their ridiculous idea generating prowess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dont-take-it-too-seriously&quot;&gt;Don’t take it too seriously&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing you should know is that whilst this is a contest and our guests will be taking it deadly seriously, you shouldn’t take it seriously at all! Believe nothing you hear, as we’ll all just be making it up as we go along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The topics discussed are entirely random, so if there’s any correlation or similarity with real world events, it’s either  entirely coincidental or a product of your own imagination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-comes-next&quot;&gt;What comes next&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recording of the podcast is going to start soon. I’m aiming to record a batch of episodes and then release them as a series in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll be able to download the podcast from the Apple Podcasts app, &lt;a href=&quot;https://badideas.podcast.johnpe.art/feed/podcast.rss&quot;&gt;subscribe directly to the feed&lt;/a&gt;, or just &lt;a href=&quot;/episodes/&quot;&gt;listen to episodes on this website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to be a guest on the podcast, there’s still time!  More details can be found in this &lt;a href=&quot;/be-a-guest/&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://badideas.podcast.johnpe.art/posts/2019/01/30/introducing-department-of-bad-ideas/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://badideas.podcast.johnpe.art/posts/2019/01/30/introducing-department-of-bad-ideas/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Be a guest on the Department of Bad Ideas</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;At its most simple, the Department of Bad Ideas is a gameshow. That means that, for every episode, we need contestants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you think you are great at coming up with bonkers solutions to ridiculous and complex problems, then now is your chance to prove it. That’s right; you can be a contestant on this very odd pod.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to be on the Department of Bad Ideas, all you have to do is get in touch. You can do that via Twitter – &lt;a href=&quot;https:/www.twitter.com/podofbadideas&quot;&gt;@PodofBadldeas&lt;/a&gt; – or via email at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:podcast&amp;#64;johnpe.art&quot;&gt;podcast@johnpe.art&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there’s a slot available on an upcoming episode, then you’re hired!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-you-need-to-know&quot;&gt;What you need to know&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You’ll need to be available for around 1 hour to record the episode.&lt;/strong&gt; This might be after work on a weekday, or on a weekend. We can schedule around your availability and mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As a contestant on the podcast, you’ll need to do a little bit of homework in advance.&lt;/strong&gt; You’ll need to prepare three, five-minute pitches ahead of the recording. You can present however you like, but remember it’s an audio podcast. You can &lt;a href=&quot;/posts/2019/01/30/introducing-department-of-bad-ideas/&quot;&gt;find more information about the format of the show in this blog post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Appearing on the show is unpaid and voluntary&lt;/strong&gt;. I’m not making any money from producing this podcast at all, and so I can’t pay you either. This is just for fun. If that changes, then I’ll agree a fair amount for your time with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recording takes place in London.&lt;/strong&gt; That’s where I’ll be, and I’ll need to record you. Again, I can’t pay for your travel — this is just for fun and I’m not making money from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anything we record will be published on the internet.&lt;/strong&gt; If you’re not comfortable with that, please don’t put yourself forward. The podcast will be edited, so if you fluff your pitches or want to try again during the recording session, that’s fine. I reserve the right to not use content if it’s of a poor quality, or I think it’ll get me or you into trouble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you want to do it with someone else, you can.&lt;/strong&gt; Just let me know who you both are, and we can sort it out. You’d both need to prepare your own content, and can compete in a head-to-head episode.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://badideas.podcast.johnpe.art/posts/2019/01/30/be-our-guest/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://badideas.podcast.johnpe.art/posts/2019/01/30/be-our-guest/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
